Guide to the Charles Joseph Levy Collection of Victoriana
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Ephemera, Series I
  - Benjamin Disraeli
    - Clippings - portraits, pictures, texts, 1877-1886, undated
      The following are included: - Benjamin Disraeli depicted as the ghost of Harrington - Lord Beaconsfield - Benjamin Disraeli caricature with caption, "One Ward for the Fenien Prisoners, and how many for the 'Shaughraum?'" - Print of Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield - Lord Beaconsfield, from the painting by Sir J. E. Millair, Rischgitz Collection - The Earl of Beaconsfield, from the painting by Sir J. E. Millair, National Portrait Gallery - Benjamin Disraeli, after the portrait by A. E. Challon (2 copies) - "Disraeli," from an etching by Pilotell - The Earl of Beaconsfield, from a photo by Hughes and Mullins - Lord Beaconsfield - "Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield" - "The Right Hon. Benjamin Disraeli, M. P." - "The Earl of Beaconsfield" - "Lord Beaconsfield at the Lord Mayor's Banquet in Guildhall, London" - "The Queen's visit to Hughenden: At Hight Wycombe Railway Station," [1877 December 15] - "Hughenden Manor, Buckinghamshire" - "Mr. Disraeli telling the House of Commons his story about 'dry champagne'" - "Lord Beaconsfield at the Banquet in Guildhall" - "Mr. Disraeli Introducing His Reform Bill in the House of Commons" - "Funeral of Lord Beaconsfield at Hughenden" (2 copies) - "Peace with Honor: Reception of Lord Beaconsfield and Lord Salisbury at Charing Cross" - "Hughenden Church" (2 copies) - Hughenden Manor, Buckinghamshire - Disraeli, Benjamin: biographical sketch - Clipping about "Primrose Day," 1886 April 19 - "Was the Earl of Beaconsfield a Representative Jew?"
  - Dickens
    - 20 illustrations from Dombey & Son, 1836 (Box 1)
    - 12 Lossing Barritt illustrations from Bleak House, 1853
    - Clippings, 1871, undated
      The following are included: - The room in which Charles Dickens wrote, from a drawing by S. L. Fildes, Harper's Weekly, 1871 January 7 - Portrait of Charles Dickens - Installment from "Master Humphrey's Clock," Philadelphia Sunday Courier - The will of Charles Dickens with a poem titled, "Dickens in Camp" - A Curious Medley
  - Miscellaneous, 1835-1912, undated; 5
    The following are included: - List of toasts, Carlisle and Silloth Bay Railroad and Dock Dinner, 1835 August 31 - At Home Invitation, Governor-General Gladstone, Government House, Johannesburg, 1912 January 12 - Calendar, First Baptist Church, Batvia, New York, 1907 February 3 - Special pass, Children's Fete, Hyde Park, 1887 June 22 - 2 admission tickets, H. M. S. Collingwood, 1882 November 22 - Calendar back: Shakespere Calendar, London, 1900 - Calendar back: The Tennyson Calendar, London, Marcus Ward & Co., 1895 - Admission ticket to the Royal Colosseum, 1863 - "Places of Interest near Inverness," The Station Hotel, Inverness - Printed program of toasts, Royal Agricultural Society of England - 4 cards soliciting aid for an orphan, Hilda Jane Hughes, British Orphan Society - 2 calling cards of Mr. Sherlock Holmes - 2 calling cards of J. H. Watson, M. D. - Stationery from "The Gladstone," Narragansett Pier, Rhode Island - Wedding breakfast invitation - Guide to H. M. S. Inflexible - Fink, Clarence M.: Typescript of "Barking up the Wrong Tree" - Anderson, Chester G.: Photocopy of typescript, "Curse you, George Orwell! Or, Should Boys have Sweethearts?" - Shell-decorated pocket notebook - "The American War in 1779," extract from Political Magazine, 1870 August, printed on satin - Christmas card to "Dear Alfred" (Prince Alfred of Saxe-Cobury) - Clipping of photograph of the Late H. R. H. Alfred, Hereditary Prince of Saxe-Cobury-Gotha - Anecdote about a "Jeweled Golden Cuspidor," mounted on board
- Ephemera - Addenda, Series II
  - Clippings - Pictorial - Portrait, undated (Box 1)
    The following are included: - Viscount Palmerston - The Prince Consort, mounted with Prince Albert at the age of twenty - Joseph Conrad - Viscount Melbourne - Sir Robert Peel - Gladstone, the Grand Old Man of Victorian politics, mounted with William Ewart Gladstone - Silhouette of Queen Victoria - "Pantheon of Victorian Letters," including George Eliot and Sir Walter Scott - Sir Edwin Chadwick - John Browne
  - Clippings - Pictorial - Other
    - Scrapbook of Victorian crests and seals, undated (Box 9 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings, undated (Box 9 (Oversize))
    - 320 illustrations clipped from Victorian bloods and thrillers, undated (Box 1)
    - Other pictorial clippings, 1866-1893, undated (Box 2)
      The following are included: - Cartoon of William Gladstone over quote by Queen Victoria - Cartoon of George Bernard Shaw over quote by H. H. Munro - The Queen's first Privy Council - The House of Lords debating Home Rule for Ireland, 1893 September 9 - "Parisian Toilets and Fashions," Harper's Weekly, 1866 June 30 - Black and white engraving of a dinner party by George Cruikshank - Black and white print of a mailcoach - Black and white print of "The Improved Street Railway Carriage" - Photograph of firemen in uniform - Black and white print of "The Miseries of an Omnibus" - Black and white print with 4 miniature John C. Bourne lithographs - Black and white print of 3 mugs commemorating the Victoria-Albert royal marriage - Black and white print of a statuette of Queen Victoria - Black and white print of a drawing by Queen Victoria - Illustration of Victorian parlour maids
  - Clippings - Printed, 1815-1900, undated (Box 2)
    The following are included: - The Times, London, No. 9554, 1815 June 22 - "When Housekeeping Became a Science," by James Marston Fitch - "Author and Heroine of 'Little Women' Louisa May Alcott," mounted on board - "Important Recent Books," from Vol. 1, No. 1, North American Notes and Queries, 1900 June - Poem, To the Queen (Victoria), 1851 March - Clipping of advertisement for "Edison's Latest Phonograph" - Reproduction of a handbill advertising Thomas Cook's first tour, 1841
  - Clippings - Printed - Oversize (Box 6)
  - Manuscripts, Etc.
    - Frederic Harrison: Page proofs of book, Studies in Early Victorian Literature, with manuscript corrections, undated (Box 2)
      Accompanied by an autograph letter, signed, from Frederic Harrison to "My Dear Sir," 1895 March 12
    - Columbian Diary of Morris W. Seymour, a Litchfield lawyer, 1885
    - Account book, [1868-1869?]
    - Account book, with a recipe for gluten bread enclosed, 1854-1860
    - The Second Meriden Mutual Benefit Building and Loan Association - account book for Mr. O. N. Bartlett, Meriden, Connecticut, 1888
    - Account book, 1852-1856
    - U. S. Army Paymaster's Report, 1863 May 31
    - No. 1 Watch, Station, Quarter, and Fire Bills, etc., 1881
    - Song book, circa 1820
    - Conduct and Lesson Report of William S. Edwards, Sing Sing, New York, 1848 September
    - Receipt for wood, Memphis, Tennessee, 1864 November 30
    - Charges and Specifications preferred against Charles H. Parkhurst, Captain of Company C of the Eleventh Regiment of Rhode Island Volunteers, 1863
    - Charges and Specifications preferred against John Talbot Pitman, Lieutenant Colonel of the Eleventh Regiment, Rhode Island Volunteers, 1863
  - Disraeli Packet, undated (Box 2)
    The following are included: - Cartoon of Lord John Russell over a quote by B. Disraeli - The Young Mr. Disraeli, mounted with Benjamin Disraeli, Earl of Beaconsfield - Monted post office telegrams from Mr. Disraeli to W. R. Callender
  - Engravings
    - "The Environs of London," engraved by W. Hughes, undated (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - 19th Century American Authors
    - Jesty Family Papers - Documents, etc., undated (Box 2)
    - Jesty Family Papers - Correspondence, undated
    - 19th century American Authors - Autographs, undated
      The following are included: - Hannah More, on paper, accompanied by a print - Francis Marion Crawford, on a photograph - Dusven, on card - Cyrus W. Field, on card - M. A. Harnig, on card - Edmund C. Stedman, on card - J. N. Wainaenighlo, on tag - D. Wilmot, on paper
  - Advertising Material, 1885-1894, undated; 5 (Box 2)
    The following are included: - Noble Thoughts from Tennyson Calendar, 1894 - Every Day Calendar, Marcus Ward and Co., London, 1891 - Wittier Calendar, Houghton Mifflin, Boston, 1887 - Lowell Calendar, Houghton Mifflin, Boston, 1885 - Tradecard for Singer Manufacturing Co., 1891 - Advertising card for S. H. Street and Co., June Calendar
  - Advertisting Material - Oversize, 1900, undated (Box 6)
    The following are included: - Catalogue of Trimmed Hats, Western Bargain Millinery Company, Chicago - Calendar advertisement for the Grand Union Tea Co., Brooklyn, New York, 1900
  - Miscellaneous Material, 1851-1922, undated; 6 (Box 2)
    The following are included: - Poem, "The Absent-Minded Beggar," printed in manuscript form with the signature of Rudyard Kipling, 1899 - Poem, "On the Inestimable Timing," written on a lace doily, 1851 December 16 - Official score card, World Championship Series, 1889 - Card game, Portrait Authors, Noyes and Snow, Worcester, Massachusetts, 1873 - Elementary School Certificate for Alice A. Merrill, 1922 June 16 - Card of British flag with manuscript note: bon voyage - Assorted Christmas cards - Victorian valentines
  - Pictorial Material
    - Daguerreotypes of a woman and a man, cased, undated (Box 2)
    - Cartes-de-visite, undated (Box 2)
  - Pictorial Miscellany
    - Series of 8 stereographs depicting the story of a French cook, Keystone View Co., 1903 (Box 2)
    - Postcard titled "London after dark", undated (Box 2)
    - Color print of 4 animal hunt scenes, undated (Box 10 (Oversize))
    - Color print of 4 scenes (with identical copies) of 19th century women, undated (Box 10 (Oversize))
    - Black and white print of Queen Victoria, mounted on board, undated (Box 2)
    - Corn family crest, undated (Box 9 (Oversize))
    - 18 cut-outs of women dressed in fashions from the 19th century, possibly from a catalogue of the period, undated (Box 2)
    - Card, "Hopping to find you well", undated (Box 2)
    - Poster lithograph of Queen Victoria, Toronto Lithographing Co., undated (Box 11 (Oversize))
    - Poster of the Prince of Wales, Montreal Family Herald and Weekly Star Supplement, "The Crown Pictures" series, 1885 (Box 11 (Oversize))
    - Poster of Queen Victoria, Montreal Family Herald and Weekly Star Supplement, "The Crown Pictures" series, 1885 (Box 11 (Oversize))
- Material Not Listed by Levy, Series III
  - Portraits
    - Color portrait of a man seated at a table, by D. Maclise, 1839 (Box 10 (Oversize))
    - Color portrait of a woman, undated (Box 10 (Oversize))
  - Manuscript Material
    - Ainsworth, William Harrison - Autograph letter (fragment) to [C. W. Day], 1852 May 3 (Box 3)
      Accompanied by Ainsworth's signature and a printed caricature of Ainsworth
    - Doyle, Richard - Autograph letter, signed, to [Lady Hobart], [18--] March 23 (Box 3)
    - Stedman, Edmund Clarence - Autograph letter, signed, to Mr. Houghton, 1888 January 2 (Box 3)
    - Stedman, Edmund Clarence - introduction to work, 1875-1889 (Box 3)
  - Printed Material
    - Black and white print of "Rugby School, Warwickshire", undated (Box 3)
    - Royal Family Memorabilia, undated (Box 3)
  - Advertising
    - 24 cigarette cards, depicting British birds and their eggs, issued by Godfrey Phillips, Ltd., undated (Box 3)
    - Collection of letterheads from various companies, undated (Box 3)
    - Poster advertisement for Dunham, Buckley & Co., New York, undated (Box 10 (Oversize))
- Objects, Series IV
  - Ephemera
    - 21 tiepin heads, undated (Box 4)
    - Beaded book mark, undated (Box 4)
    - Brocade book cover, undated (Box 4)
    - British flag, unhemmed, printed on flannel, undated (Box 4)
  - Ephemera - Addenda
    - Sailmaker's palm, undated (Box 4)
    - Button, stamped with candlestick, undated (Box 4)
    - Sunday school medal, Heywood, Bethel Street, 1880 July 3 (Box 4)
    - Pocket mirror and comb, undated (Box 4)
    - Wooden trinket box marked "Hallstatt", undated (Box 4)
    - Button with Connecticut state seal, undated (Box 4)
    - Collection of 25 Victorian seals, undated (Box 4)
    - Bracelet, undated (Box 5)
    - Brooch, undated (Box 5)
    - Miniature mug, undated (Box 5)
    - Pair of sunglasses, undated (Box 5)
    - Tatted bureau scarf, undated (Box 8 (Oversize))
    - 6 crocheted doilies, undated (Box 8 (Oversize))
    - 10 lace doilies, undated (Box 8 (Oversize))
    - Embroidered bureau scarf, undated (Box 8 (Oversize))
    - Linen eyelet dust cover, undated (Box 8 (Oversize))
    - Commemorative medal celebrating the 60th year of Queen Victoria's reign, 1887 (Box 5)
    - Monarch printing plate, undated (Box 5)
    - Serving knife and fork in leather case, undated (Box 5)
    - Small box containing scraps of Egyptian papyrus, undated (Box 5)
    - Carving set of a knife, fork, and sharpener, in a leather case, undated (Box 8 (Oversize))
    - Restricted Fragile, undated; Series V (Box 12)
      Box 12 (glass negatives): Restricted Fragile Material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
      - Glass plate negatives, undated (Box 12)